SHWETA AGARWAL

JAVA DEVELOPER

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Self-motivated IT professional with **5.5 years** of experience and a proven Knowledge in Retails and Insurance domain using J2EE technology in Big MNC's and **4 years** of experience in self employed Web development startup. Ambitious to develop User friendly and secured web applications using Java framework. **Hands on experience** in **Sales force** on **analyze the processes**, **Design the CRM workflows in Sales force**, and also provide **custom solutions** for specific business requirements. Completed multiple trainings in **Trailhead** by Salesforce. **Aiming to Work** in a globally competitive environment on challenging assignment that shall yield the twin benefits of the job satisfaction and a steady-paced professional growth.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

HEP Infotech, Noida / June 2018 to Present

HEP **Infotech**, a software development company deals in Website Design & Development and Maintenance, Mobile Responsive Websites, E-Commerce Website Development, Customized Software Development, Mobile Apps, Digital Marketing, Search Engine Optimization (SEO), Social Media Optimization (SMO). We have worked with many big clients and delivered satisfactory results.

TECHNOLOGIES / TOOLS/ ROLES:

Wordpress, Mailchimp, PHP, CSS, Server Administration, Designing, Business Strategy, Marketing Tools, SVN, Deployment, Spring Boot, Angular JS

CSC India Pvt. Ltd , Noida / June 2013 to Oct 2014

Client – US-LIFE-nbAServices-D (nbA Services) - JAVA DEVELOPER

PROJECT OVERVIEW

NBA is designed to provide new business solution for Life Insurance and Annuities automates the process from insurance request tounderwriting and finally issuing/declining the request. It provides end-to-end new business solution that includes integrated administrative cash management, communications and document management, supports multiple products, distribution channels and administration systems.

ROLES & RESPONSIBILITIES

- Develop, test and implement new requirements and its integration with components/products like AWD, VPMS, CyberLife etc.
- ♦ Test, maintain and recommend software improvements to ensure strong functionality and optimization
- Make good technical decisions that provide solutions to business Challenges

- Shwetagarg07@gmail.com
- 9654244768
- B-10, Sector-53, Noida
 G.B.Nagar (U.P)-201301

PROFILE OVERVIEW

Current Employer: HEP InfoTech Experience (Years): 5.5 + 4 Yrs

EDUCATION

B.Tech – CS (May 2009)

Vishveshwarya Institute of Engineering & Technology Greater Noida

Senior Secondary– 86% **Higher Secondary**– 86%

LOCATION

Current: Noida Preferred: Noida

TECHNOLOGIES

Platform : Java , JSP, Springs MVC Framework, Hibernate, Rest API

Database : Oracle 10g , MySql
Tools Used : Edit Plus, Clear Case

Application server: Web Sphere Application Developer

HCL Technologies, Noida / Apr 2010 - May 2013

Client – Jones Apparel Group / April 2011 to May 2013 - Product Developer

PROJECT OVERVIEW

JAG works on Teamcenter, a PLM Product, which deals in Apparels, Foot wears and Accessories. It helps in managing all processes of the product from its conception through design and manufacture.

ROLES & RESPONSIBILITIES

- Design, Estimation, Coding and testing the enhancements to Meet the client requirements.
- Generate and automate reports from databases as per client requirements.
- Defect Fixing and Analysis.

TECHNOLOGIES

Platform: Java , JSP, Springs MVC Framework, Hibernate,

Teamcenter Enterprise/Unified

Database : Oracle 10g , MySql

Tools Used : Edit Plus, Clear Case ,PM Smart

Application server: JBoss Server

Client - Mc Donald's Corporation USA / July 2010 to Apr 2011 - JAVA DEVELOPER

PROJECT OVERVIEW

RFM or Restaurant File Management, which is a Content Management Project Which is developed for supporting the POS application for MCD. The restaurant Menu Data across from all restaurants from MCD is effectively Managed Using the RFM's unified Application.

ROLES & RESPONSIBILITIES

- Design, Estimation, Coding and testing the enhancements to Meet the client requirements.
- Generate and automate reports from databases as per the client requirement.
- ♦ Defect Fixing and Analysis.

TECHNOLOGIES

Platform : Java , J2EE, Velocity, Struts , Spring

Database : Oracle 10g

Tools Used: RAD 7, Tortoise SVN, Clear Case

Application server: Web Sphere Application Developer 6.1

KEY SKILLS

- Effective in working independently and collaboratively in teams
- Excellent communication skills.
- Learning new things required for carrier growth

SIGNIFICANT ACCOMPLISHMENT

- Awarded for CSC Global Recognition Program in CSC
- Awarded for Execution Excellence in CSC
- Awarded Certificate of Excellence as a 'Best New Joinee' in HCL
- Awarded for 'Value Creation Ideas' in HCL
- Being a **College Topper** in BTECH.